AMELINE NUSSBAUMER

Chemin de la Moraine 2 1008 Prilly, Switzerland ameline.nussbaumer@gmail.com +254 745 120732

eLearning & Digital Content Creator

PROFILE

Autonomous and flexible professional with 5 years experience managing online and blended adult learning projects in international organisations. Strong experience in the design and production of interactive learning resources, well-versed in graphic design and communications. Teamplayer, comfortable in multi-cultural contexts.

EDUCATION

MSc in COMPARATIVE & INTERNATIONAL EDUCATION

University of Oxford | UK 2013 - 2014

BA (Hons) in EDUCATION & MODERN LANGUAGES

University of Cambridge | UK 2008 - 2012

IT SKILLS

- Authoring Tools (Captivate, Storyline, Mohive)
- LMS (CrossKnowledge, Moodle)
- Graphic design (Adobe Suite)
- Information Management (Office, Slack, Trello, Jive)
- Communications (Hootsuite)

LANGUAGES

- French (mothertongue)
- English (bilingual)
- German (working proficiency)
- Spanish (basic)

EXPERIENCE

A Rocha Kenya (Conservation NGO) | Watamu, KE

Jan 2020 - August 2020

Field experience during which I was responsible for fundraising, communication, and local capacity-building initiatives.

- Led international grant applications and crowdfunding campaigns
- Managed external communication: website, social media channels, annual report, newsletter, etc.
- Designed local training programme in partnership with the University of St Andrews (UK)

International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) | Geneva, CH July 2016 - Dec 2019

As Techno-Pedagogical Engineer, I managed learning initiatives liaising with internal experts and external providers. As Applications Trainer, I produced online learning courses, conducted trainings of trainers to build internal training capacity, and supported the digital transformation of the division.

- Managed the design and development of trainings in various formats: eLearning, blended, mobile app, face-to-face
- Produced user-friendly learning resources to facilitate colleagues' adoption and use of new digital tools
- Delivered training of trainers and regular internal workshops on training practices and digital tools
- Designed and facilitated online communities of practice and online learning paths

United Nations Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR) | Geneva, CH

Sept 2014 - June 2016

As eLearning officer, I gained broad experience in the development, promotion and evaluation of online training courses, as well as key skills in project management and communication.

- Facilitated, translated, and evaluated eLearning courses
- Co-organized an international Forum (logistics and content)

REFERENCES

Dr Feena May

feena@theinspiringcompany.com

+41 79 744 3000

Barbara Hunziker

Ex-Director, Learning & Development, ICRC Dep. Director in Operations Dept, ICRC bhunziker@icrc.org +41 22 730 3129